

## ALWYN EBENEZER J

- +91 9940520039
- win011990@gmail.com
- **O Chennai -INDIA**

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

NX-CAD 12.0

CREO 3.0

CATIA •••C

ANSYS •••OO

# **PLM SOFTWARES**

TEAM CENTER -12 PRO/INTRA LINK

## **LANGUAGES**

ENGLISH



TAMIL



# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Knowledgeable in CAD application software
- CAD: I-DEAS NX environment (3D and 2D drafting)
- Analytical skills Complex problem solving.

### **SUMMARY**

Problem-solving mechanical design engineer with 6+ years of experience in different products. Dedicated knowledge of technologies, tools and best practices in mechanical design using NX-CAD and engineering drawings. Able to design and fabricate equipment and test and improve prototypes. Worked independently and committed to providing high-quality service with a focus on accomplish engineering goals, health, safety, and environmental issues.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### 2018 - till date

Presently working at FLENDER INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED

(Carve-out from SIEMENS LIMITED on Jan 2021)

Designation: Senior Design Engineer (Mechanical Developer)
Deputation to FRANCE: From 16/06/2022 - 13/07/2022
To develop the new standard components master model using Expressions by NX-CAD with FRANCE team
Roles: Dedicated resource for Flender Graffenstaden projects, to develop standard ,non standard turbo gear boxes and components like (casing, Gear shafts, bearings, coupings, labyrinth seal, clutches, etc..) using NX-CAD

# <u> 2017 – 2018</u>

Royal Enfield, Chennai. Deputed by **SUNWELLS OXYGEN INDIA PRIVATE LIMITED**. Department: **R&D**Designation: **Design Engineer** 

### <u> 2014 - 2016</u>

**GGS information services India Pvt.Ltd**, Chennai Working for **Caterpillar India Pvt** projects

## **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION**

Year of passing: 2014

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering, First Class, CGPA: 7.8

Sri Venkateshwara Institute Of Science & Technology, Tiruvallur, Chennai – 631 203

Year of Passing: 2010

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering, First Class, 85 Percentages

MAJOR ROLES: DME MTMR (Machine Tools Maintenance & Repairs) (SWC)

A.M.K. Technological Polytechnic College, Chembarambakkam, Chennai – 600 077